Just tapping in to say, if I cannot criticize your leader or a candidate three years out from the election year, that too is a symptom of fascism.
I would like to preface everything I'm about to say by saying that I am an organizer who just so happens to make content.
I do not have that much power and influence.
But if I did, baby, let me tell you, your life would be better.
I swear.
Now, my issue is, is the core of the Democratic base is only focused on short term visible decision making, i.e. voting, legislative advocacy, special elections, primary elections and midterms.
All things that I do, mind you.
And these things, while helpful in their own way, will not stop fascism.
Because the right wing is focused on the two higher levels of power, which is shaping the agenda, figuring out who was at the table and setting up who was on the menu long term and also shaping institutions and influencing culture.
So, as organizers, our focus should be the same.
How do we create better institutional, not rhetorical, not symbolic, not ceremonial?
How do we create better institutional conditions for us to organize under?
This means setting a long term political agenda, including expanding the court, including getting money out of politics, including expanding the election in order for people to get different forms of representation through party affiliations.
We also need to shift power away from the corporate, the corporate oligarchy that is currently controlling our government and put the power back into the hands of the people whose labor actually sustains this fucking economy.
Because the tiny hand fascist has always and will always be a threat to democracy, but so is refusing to have an actual primary process if we're being for real.
And also, pandering to white suburban wine moms who vote with their Republican husbands every single time and abandoning your base by moving to the right is not only delusional, but it is terrible campaign strategy.
Let's be for real.
Zoran's campaign just showed us that people power can beat organized money, but we have to be serious about having a strategy and a platform in order to make that happen.
If you made it this far into the video, go ahead and comment a red heart emoji because I miss you guys so much.
Oh my.